Venkatesh Gutta 🕡 Featured

Software Engineer seeking assignments in Software Development, Application Programming, Program Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, HTML, Javascript, Entity Framework, ASP. Net MVC, JQuery, ADO. Net, CSS, SQL Server, C#. Net, TFS



Current Designation: Software Engineer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

Current Company: Agility E Services Pvt. Ltd Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [IT]

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Software Developer, Software Development, Application Programming, Program

Management, Project Management, Requirement Gathering, System Analysis, HTML, Javascript, Entity Framework, ASP. Net

MVC, JQuery, ADO. Net, CSS, SQL Server, C#. Net, TFS

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 18-Jan-21

Summary

Having 5 Years of experience in the Application Design and Development.

Experience on .Net Platform Technologies in Web applications of 3.5 and 4.0 frameworks.

Having Experience on SQL Server 2008 and Oracle 11g.

Have good Experience on client-side technologies HTML,CSS,JavaScript,JQuery

Experience in developing and deploying web applications, windows applications.

Experience in analyzing, designing, debugging and developing software.

Having Experience on developing Crystal Reports.

Having good knowledge on developing WCF Services.

Having Experience on developing web services and windows services.

Having Knowledge on Azure.

Work Experience

Agility E Services Pvt. Ltd as Software Engineer

Oct 2019 to Till Date

Title FOCIS

Environment C#.NET,ASP.NET,Oracle 11g,web services, JQuery, Ajax, AZURE

Duration OCT 2019 to Till Date.

Description

Project Title : FOCIS (Transport Tracking System for Agility Logistics)

Team Size : 12 Members

Environnent : Asp.Net, C#.Net,ADO.NET, SQL Server 2008, JQuery

Role [: Team member

Duration : October-2019 to till date

Project Description : FOCIS application is "Transport Tracking System" for Agility Logistics, Providing automated tracking service for shipment and providing the best route map for transportation based on user requirement and tracking all shipment information. Main features are Transport Route Engine, Shipment Booking, Tracking Shipment, Automated Shipment Status, Security Management, Rule Management, Document Management, Validation Management, etc

VSoft Technologies Pvt.Ltd as Software Engineer

Apr 2015 to Oct 2019

Title Cheque Truncation System (CTS)

Environment C#.NET,ASP.NET,ADO.Net,Oracle 11g,web services, windows services,

WCF Services

Duration April 2015 to OCT-2019.

Description

eDesk Capture enables you to capture images and data of items at the branches or at the service branch. Typically, the branches receive different types of items like On-Us cheques, outstation or inter-city cheques, local clearing cheques, and high value cheques from its customers for outward clearing.

During the capture process, those items that are erroneously captured are repaired, reviewed, and balanced by the operator using the eDesk application. The Extract file that is generated by the system can be used by the core application of the bank.

eDesk Capture is an application in the VSoft eDesk product family. Operators use eDesk Capture to control the capture device during sorting. System administrators and supervisors use eDesk to set up and maintain the system. Using eDesk allows you to store information electronically.

Responsibilities:

Developed Extract Programs for different clients.

Involved in front end design and controls using ASP.NET.

Developed web pages using JavaScript for Client side Validation.

Developed modules of the application in ASP.NET and involved in writing C# classes.

Used ADO.NET objects for consistent access of data from Oracle database.

Involved in fixing the bugs in the web applications.

Involved in fixing the bugs in the windows applications.

Creating web services and windows services.

Developed Crystal reports for different clients.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (IT) from Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University (JNTU) in 2014

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Microsoft.Net 3.5 ,4.0	
C#.net, Web Service	
ASP.NET,ASP.NET MVC	
ADO.NET,Entity Framework	
HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery	
SQL Server 2008 R2, Oracle 11g	
SVN, TFS	

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English				
Telugu				

1/22/2021

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time